准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
鲜花美人计
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
分镜指导
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
每每清晨空气香甜的时候
I always make lots of money
我常常都会赚到大钱
when the morning air smells this good
怎么回事
What in Finnegan's Footlocker?
海之霸
痞老板好像要搬走了  蟹老板
Looks like Plankton is moving away, Mr. K
最好有这回事
Yeah, right
估计有什么阴谋诡计
He's planning something
这个嘛  尤金
Well, Eugene--
我要永远搬走了
I'm leaving for good
我跟凯伦要在统治世界之前环游世界
Karen and I are gonna
travel the world before I take it over
最好有这回事
Yeah, right
那好吧
Right, okay
再见了
Bye-bye, then
有缘再见  小子
I'll see you later, kid
虽然你还在  但是我
You're still here, but I--
我已经在想念你了
I already miss you
行了  给我得了
All right, that's enough
走吧
Let's go
永别了  蟹黄堡的秘密配方
Farewell, Krabby Patty secret formula
永别了  裤头村
Farewell, Bikini Bottom
最好有这回事
Yeah, right
等一下
Wait a minute
我自由了
I'm free
好耶  宝贝
Yeah, baby
我自由了
I'm free
没痞老板  我自由了
No more Plankton, me free
自由  自由
Free, free
再也没有痞老板了
No more Plankton, huh?
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs?
怎么了  小子
What is it, boy-o?
花盆花店
全新开张
价格实惠
花盆花店
FlowerPot Florist?
我可爱死价格实惠的插花了
I just love floral arrangements at affordable prices
马上就去跟店主套套近乎
Well, I'd better make friends with the owner right away
绝对不能再跟人家结梁子
I don't want another crazy feud with him too
你好
Hello
欢迎光临花盆花店  哈
Welcome to the FlowerPot, huh?
我是店主  佩图尼亚
I'm the owner, Petunia
矮  牵  牛
我是蟹
Well, I'm Mr--
不必向我自报姓名了
You don't have to tell me who you are
你就是蟹老板  哈
You're Mr. Krab, huh?
你开蟹堡王的  哈
And you run the Krusty Krab, huh?
我最爱的餐厅就这家  哈
It's my favorite restaurant, huh?
很高兴认识你  佩图尼亚
Well, nice to meet you, Petunia
我只是想顺道过来
I just wanted to stop by
欢迎你来到这附近
and welcome you to the neighborhood
随时都可以顺道过来  哈
You stop by any time, huh?
那就谢谢你
Well, thank ye
她还真是好心
What a nice lady
老螃蟹中计了
Krabs is actually buying it
我知道  哈
I know, huh?
使出鲜花美人计
This friendly florist farce
定能偷到蟹黄堡的秘密配方
will finally get that Krabby Patty secret formula
你好  新邻居
Hello, new neighbor
我喜欢你家的花
I like your flowers
我知道
I get it
有时候就应该歇下脚
Sometimes you just gotta stop
闻闻金鱼草  哈
and smell the snapdragons, huh?
我要买这朵大的
I wanna buy this big one
那朵是非卖品
That one's not for sale
不过这朵可以免费送给你
But you can have this one for free
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
回来做蟹黄堡
get back to your grill
我连鼻子都能喷出点餐单了
I've got orders coming out of my nose
遵命  先生
Aye-aye, sir
再见  女士
And bye-bye, ma'am
真对不起  小姐
Sorry about that, miss
海绵宝宝净让人头
SpongeBob can be a real pain in the--
佩图尼亚
Petunia
很高兴认识你
Enchanté
在下章鱼哥
Je suis Squidward
如果需要帮忙摆花的话
If you ever need any help arranging your flowers
就告诉我一声
give me a holler
把我当作你的朱兰老爸
Think of me as your "Pogonia Pappy"
向朱兰老爸送朵康乃馨  哈
Here's a complimentary carnation
for "Pogonia Pappy," huh?
别看我
Look away
我丑死了
I'm hideous
这套伪装好危险
This disguise is dangerous
几束花之后
尽情欣赏黄水仙  哈
Enjoy the daffodils, huh?
完全没人怀疑
No one suspects a thing
准备好启动
So are you ready
鲜花美人计第二阶段了吗  佩图尼亚
for Faux Florist phase two, Petunia?
马上就好  亲爱的
Soon, my dear
就快了
All in good time
不过插花不是很棒吗
But isn't this arrangement fabulous?
送花时间到
Time to make a delivery
鲜花力量大
Power to the flower
万岁
Hooray
别抠鼻子了
Don't pick your nose
挑朵花吧
Pick a flower
也太可爱了吧
Isn't this lovely?
好好欣赏
Enjoy
再见
Bye now
鲜花力量大
Power to the flower
贵安  佩图尼亚
Bonjour, Petunia
我想买一束花
I would like to buy a bouquet
又回来了  哈
Back again, huh?
建议你少买点  章鱼哥先生
You'd better cut back, Mr. Tentacles
你今天已经买四束花了
This is your fourth bouquet today
那个
Well, uh--
章鱼哥先生
Mr. Squidward?
回去工作
Back to work
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
你省了我不少走过去的工夫
You'll save me a trip
你的蟹堡王花束准备好了  哈
Your Krusty Krab bouquets are ready, huh?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
把袋子抬走
Carry that bag
遵命  老板
Yes, sir, sir
我来抬
I got it
谢谢你  佩图尼亚
Thank you, Petunia
等会儿再过来闻花
Smell you later
成功了  谢尔顿
You did it, Sheldon
我们的花马上就会挂满蟹堡王
The Krusty Krab will be festooned with our flowers
很快秘方就能到手了
Soon we will have their formula
我感觉不太好吧
Well, I don't know about that
其实我在考虑把计划搁置一段时间
Actually, I was thinking of
putting my plan on hold for a while
什么
What?
当个全职花店店主
And becoming a full-time florist
我爱让客人满面笑容
I love making customers smile
我感觉自己真的掌握了插花的诀窍
and I really think
I have the knack for flower arranging
太好了
That's so sweet
我的小可爱想当花店店长
My widdle man wants to be a fworist
这可是我的新梦想
It's my new dream
尽情享受你的梦想吧  亲爱的
Enjoy that dream while you can, honey
你还剩大概五分钟时间
You got about five minutes
什么意思
What do you mean?
计划你不记得了吗
Don't you remember your plan?
你把炸弹花卖给蟹老板
You sell exploding flowers to Krabs
等时间到了
wait for the timers to go off
所有人全都惊慌失措
and while everyone is freaking out
你就径直走进去  取走秘方
you walk right in and take the formula
海神王的鼻毛啊  我都忘了
Neptune's nose hairs, I forgot
必须去阻止开花
I've gotta stop those flowers from blooming
保住我的新事业
and save my new career
哈
huh?
佩图尼亚
Petunia
看看你家美丽无比的花
Look how your beautiful flowers
为蟹堡王增色不少啊
have brightened up the Krusty Krab
非常好  尤金
That's great, Eugene
哈
Huh
不好意思  哈
Pardon me, huh?
别忘了这个
Don't forget this
我先把这些花弄新鲜点
I'll just freshen these florets
再带回来吧  哈
and bring them right back, huh?
不知道佩图尼亚怎么了
I wonder what's wrong with Petunia
她才没怎么了
Nothing's wrong with her
她跟我一样是完美主义者
She's a perfectionist like me
我深深爱上了她
I'm in love with her
这个秘密我彻底公开了
and I can't keep it a secret any longer
佩图尼亚
Petunia
拆引信的时间只剩一分钟了
I've got exactly one minute to defuse these bombs
我从我自家的花园摘的秋海棠  哈
I picked this begonia from my own flower garden, huh?
非常好看
That's a nice one
不过我现在不能收下  章鱼哥先生
but I can't right now, Mr. Tentacles
请你让一让
Please step aside
花店店长佩图尼亚
Petunia the florist
你是否能嫁
will you marry--
你这个恋爱脑
You loopy lovesick lummox
把我计划全搞砸了
You sabotaged my whole plan
你不仅仅玩弄了章鱼哥的心
Not only did you play with Squidward's heart
还害我损失了24束花
but you cost me 24 bouquets
大家过来踩他
I say we step on him
完蛋了  哈
Whoopsie daisy, huh?
雏 菊
佩图尼亚她鱼很好
Petunia was very nice
但我很高兴你回来了  痞老板
but I'm so glad you're back, Plankton
谢了  海绵笨笨
Thanks, SpongeBoob
你送了我最好的礼物
You've given me the greatest gift I could ever ask for
帮我腾出时间做这个
just enough time to do this
海之霸
走了  小毛茛
Let's go, buttercup
再见了
Toodle-oo
不卖花了
No more flowers
我要继续偷秘方
It's back to the secret formula for me
我的虹膜
My iris
鸢 尾
完了
Oh, no
我回来了  宝贝
I'm back, baby
哈
Huh?
海绵宝宝去游行
翻译: 1440kHz
编剧
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
住手  不准把你手上的传单
Avast, keep your proposal and propaganda mitts
贴到我门上
away from me door
你搞什么啊  我干个活而已
Come on, man, I'm just doing my job
欢迎大家前来
"Come one, come all
参加明天举行的裤头村大游行
to the Big Bikini Bottom Parade tomorrow"
好啊
Oh, boy
游行
Parade?
我参军那会儿可没少齐步走
I did enough marching when I was in the navy
可是游行可以方方便便地
But a parade is a great way
给蟹堡王免费打广
to get free advertising for the Krusty--
免费
Free?
我最爱这么组词了
That's me favorite assemblage of letters
要干什么
What do we do?
必须要造一辆花车
We're gonna have to build a float
又浪费了一天的时间
Well, that was another day wasted
你今天还没过完呢  章鱼哥先生
Your day's not over, Mr. Squidward
我要你和海绵宝宝
I want you and SpongeBob
造出来一辆蟹堡王花车
to build a Krusty Krab float
准备明天的裤头村游行
for the Bikini Bottom Parade tomorrow
好耶
Oh, yeah
你们两个只有十小时
You two have ten hours
既然你会搞艺术
And since you're the artistic type
就让你来设计
you get to design it
设计
Design?
好啊
Okay
等下  预算有多少
Wait, what's the budget?
就属这个我最满意
Well, that's the best part
预算是零
Zero budget
你们要发挥创意  使出想象力
You get to be creative and use your imagerination
想象力
Imagination
等不及要看你的旷世巨作了
Can't wait to see your masterpiece
你们两个玩得开心点
Have fun, you two
你在画什么
Whatcha drawing?
让我看看
Lemme see
我想看
I wanna see
给我看看嘛
Come on, show me
我能看吗
Can I see?
我想看
I wanna see
求你了
Please?
去看吧
Go ahead
跟我说说你的评价
Tell me how much you like it
放开了说  我都能接受
Don't worry, I can take it
首先  设计得特别好
First of all, it's genius
不过还需要一点
But it could use a little--
造就对了
Just build it
什么
What the?
章鱼哥  要上哪找造花车的材料
Squidward, where do I find building materials?
我不管
I don't care
哪都行
Anywhere
果然
Of course
我不管  哪都行
"I don't care, anywhere"
什么
What?
你好啊  哪都行
Hello, anywhere
十小时后
蟹堡王
你在干什么
What are you doing?
你睡着的样子
You know, you look like a little baby octopus
真像一只章鱼宝宝
when you're asleep
现在几点了
What time is it?
快到游行的点了
Almost parade time
已经做完了
I finished it
为你献上蟹堡王游行花车
I give you the Krusty Krab parade float
哒哒
Ta-da
蟹堡王
我把花车做得更切合主题了点
I made it a little more on theme
傻蛋主题还差不多
It's moron-themed, all right
[ moron（傻蛋）与 more on（更切合）谐音 ]
居然连我的画都没用上
You didn't even use my drawing
我用上了啊
Of course, I did
我用那幅画来补蟹黄堡上面的洞
I used it to patch up that hole in the Krabby Patty
随便你
Well, whatever
样子看着还行
It looks fine, I guess
秘方瓶的样子跟真货似的
The secret formula bottle
almost looks like the real thing
就是真货  只不过大点
It is, just bigger
我还把秘方写进里面的纸上了
I even wrote down the secret formula
on the paper inside
只有咱俩知道
Only we know
海之霸
我还把秘方写进里面的纸上了
I even wrote down the secret formula
on the paper inside
只有咱俩知道
Only we know
居然把秘方写进去了
Wrote down the secret formula?
真是白痴得恰到好处
That beautiful idiot
看来我要去参加游行了
Looks like I'm going to a parade
欢迎来到裤头村年度大游行
Welcome to the annual Bikini Bottom Parade
今天正是海底举办游行的美好日子
and it's a beautiful ocean day for it
我是帕奇帕金斯
I'm Perch Perkins
在市中心为您现场直播
coming to you live from downtown
在我身边的是今年的联合主持人
And with me is this year's co-host
举世无双的冰淇淋大王
the one and only Ice Cream King
裤头村游行
您能来是我的荣幸  陛下
It's an honor to have you, Your Majesty
该叫你大王  还是小冰
Do I call you King or Ice?
你就是那家伙
You're that guy
你是怎么从我电视跑出去的
How'd you get out of my TV
你个坏小子
you bad little boy?
你还化了妆
You're wearing makeup
你是小丑吗
Are you a clown?
我想要气球
I want a balloon
对
Yeah
好
Sure
会给你气球的
We'll get you a balloon
今年游行开场
And to kick off this year's parade
迎面走来的是裤头村中学巡游乐队
here comes
the Bikini Bottom High School marching band
就算他们不奏乐
You know, even when they're not playing
也喜欢凑一块游行
they love to march together
这个乐队实际上
The band is actually
由35个相互独立的乐队组成
made up of 35 individual bands
这些年轻人站位十分精准
Amazing precision from these youngsters
他们全都撞衫了
They all wore the same outfit
太尴尬了
How embarrassing
完美的水母
A perfect jellyfish
那居然是水母
That's a jellyfish?
一撮头发还差不多
I was gonna say a clump of hair
等下
Wait
那孩子是不是二分裂成两个生物体了
did that kid just separate into two organisms
via binary fission?
我一直都在骑车钓鱼
I've been bicycle fishing
[ binary fission（二分裂）
与 bicycle fishing（骑车钓鱼）谐音 ]
真的挺疼的
It really hurts
孩子们是不是很厉害呢
Aren't those kids amazing?
迎面过来的是谁
And what have we here?
是古怪无脑社
It's the kooky Nitwitting Club
好的
Okay
冰淇淋大王加入了他的无脑社社友们
the Ice Cream King has joined his fellow Nitwitters
以前从来没见过会有人那样开船
I've never seen anyone drive like that before
很快
Any minute now
秘密配方就会归我了
that secret formula will be mine
蟹堡王
大家看到这辆花车之后
Boy, after seeing this float
就都会冲进蟹堡王去了
everyone will rush to the Krusty Krab
你过期薯条准备得怎么样了  小子
How ya set up with those expired fries, boy-o?
十分油滋滋  老板
Good and greasy, boss
准备好了吗  章鱼哥先生
Ready, Mr. Squidward?
我没准备好
No, I'm not
海绵宝宝在我前面  害我啥都看不到
I can't see a thing with SpongeBob in front of me
太棒了
Excellent
到我们了
It's our turn
一起上场吧
Let's move it out
游行起点
接下来
Next up
出场的是拉里健身房的健壮兄弟
we have the Beefy Bros from Larry's Gym
拉里健身房
看那些头脑简单四肢发达的家伙举重
Look at those meatheads pump iron
秀肌肉的样子真是令人叹为观止
That's some impressive muscle hustle
泡芙老师来了
And here comes Mrs. Puff
她亲自当气球
As her own balloon
我好想要那颗气球
I want that balloon
派大星的石头是唯一不会飘的花车
Patrick's rock is one float that doesn't float
看起来海霸王
Looks like Bubble Bass
搭了美人鱼战士和企鹅男孩的无影船
has hitched a ride with Mermaid Man and Barnacle Boy
这是什么
And what's this?
后来者不甘示弱
Not to be outdone
是弗雷德
it's Fred
驾着好得不得了的我的腿花车
in his incredible My Leg Mobile
我的腿
My leg
我在我的腿里
I'm in my leg
我闻到了油味
I smell grease
那可不是我的味道  大王
That's not me you're smelling, King
是蟹堡王花车的味道
It's the float from the Krusty Krab
蟹堡王每天把一百多万份蟹黄堡
serving over a million Krabby Patties
卖给了成百上千的居民
daily to hundreds
上面的是大家最爱的小气鬼
There's everybody's favorite tightwad
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
他们玩了个新花样
Well, there's something new--
往场下抛薯条
french-fry confetti
来迎接你的末日吧  老螃蟹
Time to meet your doom, Krabs
秘方在十二点钟方向
Secret formula at 12:00
大家稍等
Hang on, folks
看来有人最后一刻加入了游行
It looks like the parade's got a last-minute entry
这会不会是
I'd say it's some kind of
装了轮子的变质热狗呢
rancid hot dog on wheels?
不对  各位观众
No, folks
这位一定是
I believe this is
裤头村的邪恶天才  痞老板
Bikini Bottom's own evil genius, Plankton
今年这么快就开始出乱子了
It didn't take long for anarchy to begin this year
疯狗浪来了
It's a rogue wave
东北风来了
a nor'easter
暴风雨来了
a perfect storm
是一场场混乱
It's chaos and confusion
裤头村游行的老传统了
a tradition here at the Bikini Bottom Parade
看来菜单上添了道新菜
Well, looks like there is something new on the menu
蟹堡王花车火速前进
The Krusty Krab float is coming in hot
我的腿
My leg
我的腿花车
My Leg Mobile
我们看到了一系列骨牌效应发生
And here we see the domino effect in action
我的冠军
My champion
拉里我可举不了这样的重
Larry can't lift this kind of weight
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen
这场大游行迅速失控地演变成
this parade has careened into
多灾多难又混乱的车祸现场
a calamitous catastrophe of crashing and chaos
宝贝想要拿秘方
Baby wants his secret formula
不
No
别过来  痞老板
No, Plankton
别过来
No, no
弃花车逃命
Abandon float
等等我
Wait for me
我的了
It's mine
他为啥要抢那个没用道具
Why does he want that useless prop, anyway?
因为海绵宝宝把秘方写到那张纸上了
Because SpongeBob
wrote the secret formula on that paper
等等  什么
Wait, what?
什么
What?
本地加油站的最后一辆花车
It looks like one last float from the local gas station
以易燃物的形态加入了游行
is making a combustible entry
各位观众
Well folks
这场游行现已正式认定为车祸现场
this parade has now officially been
declared an apocalypse
不  不
No, no
差点就到手了
I almost had it
走了  小子
Come on, boy-o
一起回蟹堡王
Let's go back to the Krusty Krab
我要在那罚你适当无偿加班
where I can punish you proper with unpaid overtime
因为你闹了这么一出傻事
for doing such a foolish thing
弄到了一小块
I got something--
秘方的其中一样原料
an ingredient to the secret formula
一样原料到手了
I got an ingredient
盐
一样原料到手了
I got an ingredient
盐
Salt
没错  宝贝
That's right, baby
盐
Salt
秘方里有盐
It's got salt in it
我就快破解出来了
I'm cracking the code
只要把盐加进正确的原料里
All I have to do now is add the right ingredients to salt
然后快看
and voilà
我就有蟹黄堡秘方了
I'll have the Krabby Patty secret formula
我可真是个天才
You know, I really am a genius
各位观众
Well folks
又一场裤头村游行多灾多难地结束了
another Bikini Bottom Parade ends in disaster
每年都一个样
Same as every year
有啥不行呢
Why not?
现在  我想感谢我的联合主持人
And now, I'd like to thank my co-host
冰淇淋大王
the Ice Cream King
大王
King?
我弄到气球了
I got my balloon